# JC Coles

(661) 319-2747 | jcoles1155@gmail.com | Ventura, CA | http://www.jcoles1155.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholas-coles-314495a6/

## Full Stack Developer

Full Stack Web developer with a passion for creating great products. My experience in many different work environments has taught me to adapt quickly to new technologies and tasks. As a strong IT professional, I'm excited to apply my insights with a team of other great engineers and to grow within a dynamic company.

#### SKILLS

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, SQL, PHP, Python, HTML, CSS

**TECHNOLOGIES:** MERN, LAMP, Node.js, MongoDB, Linux/Unix, React.js, Express.js, Postgres, Django, Laravel, Bootstrap, JQuery, Oauth, JWT, Github, Heroku, Insomnia, Passport, Morgan, bcrypt, Microsoft Office Suite, Wordpress, Squarespace

### **PROJECTS**

# **Game of Pure Strategy**

- Card game built out of bootstrap templates to be played locally
- Used Javascript and jQuery to create dynamically loading pages that presented an updated score
- Applied Git throughout the process for version control and tested features

### Beer Finder

- Used HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap to create views of Beer Recipe app
- Implemented authentication with sign up / log in / log out functions using Passport.js and OAuth
- Built the app with full CRUD functionality using Javascript on Node.js and frameworks; data stored using MongoDB database through Mongoose
- Used Heroku to deploy and MongoDB atlas to manage database

## https://colescarbide.com/

- Laravel site developed with PHP to showcase product and provide information on company
- Worked with thrive digital agency to implement SEO strategy
- Hosted with digital Ocean generating 500+ clicks per month over the last 2 years

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Coles Carbide Corporation** – Machinist, Bakersfield, CA

August 2017 - Present

- Operate 3-axis CNC lathes to retool other machines, and makes cuts on parts
- Managed the implementation of the inventory and warehouse management systems
- Operate supplementary shop machinery including grinders and laser etching machine

## **Surfline Corporation** – Network Technician, Ventura, CA

February 2018 - Present

- Installed cameras and routers when needed from Santa Barbra to Oxnard California
- Provided first point of contact for customers with cameras, acknowledged client and addressed needs
- Troubleshot cameras in my region during connection outages and network failures

## Madewest Brewing Company - Cellar Person, Ventura, CA

December 2019 - August 2020

- Facilitated cellar operations daily in preparation for and during brews
- Managed the dry hopping schedule for core beers and logged gravity levels of all beers daily
- Operated forklift in order to store, pack, and ship beers with stone distribution

### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly: Software Engineering Immersive, (MERN stack, Javascript, Python)

Oct 2020 – May 2021

**Ventura College:** General Education

Jan 2016 - June 2018